Guide to the Dorothy Chancellor Collection, 1885-1985
Pasadena Historical Museum
Dorothy Chancellor Collection,
1885-1985
Chancellor, Dorothy
9 boxes
Pasadena Historical Museum Pasadena, California 91103-3594
Administrative Information
Access
Collections are available for research only.
Biographical Note
Dorothy Chancellor (1910-1985) was born and raised in Pasadena. Her parents were R.O. Albany and Helen Chancellor. R.O. Albany Chancellor served as private secretary to Conway Campbell-Johnston for many years. Helen Chancellor's father was at one time Rector of Church of the Angels on Avenue 64 and R.O.A. Chancellor was its treasurer for many years. Dorothy Chancellor graduated from Pasadena High School in 1928 and went on to work in the Pasadena school system from 1929-1960. She was an office clerk at McKinley Junior High for many years and an office secretary at Muir High School at the time of her retirement. Dorothy Chancellor's aunt was Ruth Thompson, who wrote children's books including, Comrades of the Desert in 1920.
Scope and Content
The Dorothy Chancellor Collection (1885-1985) includes personal, business, and legal papers and correspondence, family photos, books, scrapbooks, artwork, and schoolwork.
Key to Arrangement
- Scrapbooks Special Collection (Box 1)
- First Alphabet Book DC3 (Box 1)
- Cloth Picture Book DC 4 (Box 1)
- Elsie and Elmer Book DC 5 (Box 1)
- Retirement papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Tax returns 1939-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence with Executive House, Victoria, B.C., Canada,1977-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Travel guides, train schedules, postcards, travel information, brochures, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- [Envelope] Photograph, poems, misc. newspapers, magazines, bulletins, 1913-1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- [Envelope] Business and personal correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- American Cancer Society certificates, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bound collection of mounted leaves (Box 3)
- History of Art by Dorothy Chancellor, seven bound folders about art history (Box 3)
- Announcements/Addresses (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Business correspondence, 1962-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Clippings, 1962-1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Drawings 1917- (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Ephemera-school work, report cards from Pasadena High School and Pasadena Junior College, correspondence), 1885-1929 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Greeting cards, post cards (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Greeting cards, post cards (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Personal correspondence, 1878-1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Photos (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Announcements/Addresses,1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bills (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Business correspondence (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1939-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Drawings, 1916- (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Ephemera, 1915-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Greeting cards/post cards, 1919-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Invitations (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous business records, 1904-1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Personal correspondence, 1889-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Photos-including school photo (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Printed matter-booklet, The Church and Her Ways, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- City Arithmetics Grade VI, by Wentworth, Smith, Shiels, 1916 (Box 6)
- An Introduction to American History, by Alice Atkinson, 1919 (Box 6)
- First Book: The Progressive Course in Reading, by George I. Aldrich, 1899 (Box 6)
- Comrades of the Desert: A Story for Boys, by Ruth Thompson. (Box 6)
- Inscribed by the author to her niece, Dorothy. News clipping pasted on inside cover, December 17, 1920.
- Hymnal, 1920 (Box 6)
- Common Prayer book, 1920 (Box 6)
- Business correspondence, 1935-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Clippings (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Ephemera-report cards, award certificates, senior citizen identification, souvenirs, school work, 1920-1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Greeting cards/Post cards (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Personal correspondence, 1884-1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Legal correspondence- (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Will of Dorothy Chancellor
  - Legal papers of estate of Harriet E. Chancellor, 1912-13
  - Arthur North Chancellor estate papers, 1949
  - Legal papers of estate of Marjorie Montgomery Ward Baker, 1959
  - Will of Robert O.A. Chancellor, 1966
- Legal correspondence, 1927-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Wills- (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Folder 1-Will of Harriott Ellen Chancellor, 1911
  - "Letters relating to various legacies left to me (Dorothy) by my (Dorothy's family," 1918-1943
  - Will of Marjorie Montgomery Ward Baker, 1912
- Photographs, daguerreotype, news clippings, Dorothy Chancellor's war ration book, English postcards (Box 8)
- A Picture Birthday Book for Boys and Girls (Box 8)
- Holy Bible (Box 8)
- Owned by Ruth Thompson and then Dorothy Chancellor, 1919.
- Baby's Kingdom (Box 8)
- Baby book, made in 1885; used for Dorothy in 1911.
- Memories of My School Days, 1920s (Box 8)
- Dorothy Chancellor's high school diploma, Pasadena High School, 1928 (Box 9)
- Graduation ceremony programs, 1928 (Box 9)
- Photograph, bookkeeping ledgers,1875 (Box 9)
- The Little Folds Paper, 6/5/04 and 6/12/04 (Box 9)
- Object Lesson A B C, 1916 (Box 9)
- What a Cook Ought to Know About Cornstarch, by Emma Churchman Hewitt (Box 9)
- Royal Baking and Pastry Cook (Box 9)